世间有两种人
There are two kinds of folks
总在思考如何杀人
who sit around thinking about how to kill people.
精神病患者和侦探小说作家
Psychopaths and mystery writers.
我属于高收入的后者  我是谁
I'm the kind that pays better. Who am I?
我是里克・卡塞尔
I'm Rick Castle.
卡塞尔
Castle.
我浑身都散发着粗犷美  是不是
I really am ruggedly handsome, aren't I?
每位作家都离不开灵感
Every writer needs inspiration,
我的灵感已经找到了
and I've found mine.
凯特・贝克特探长
Detective kate beckett.
贝克特
Beckett.
-妮基・希特  -那个角色是以你为原型
- Nikki heat? - The character he's basing on you.
很庆幸我和市长是朋友
And thanks to my friendship with the mayor,
她办案我能跟着
I get to be on her case.
要是你能打我  我会很开心
I would be happy to let you spank me.
我们一起抓过凶手
And together, we catch killers.
我们俩可是最佳拍档
We make a pretty good team, you know?
像是警界双雄[电影]  福星福将[电影]
Like starsky and hutch, turner and hooch.
你跟呼哧[福星福将的福星狗]挺像
You do remind me a little of hooch.
抱歉  宝贝
Oh, excuse me, baby. Oh.
家  温馨的家
Ah, home sweet home.
现在能把狗狗从犬舍接回来吗
Can we get midnight from the kennel now?
-收拾好就接它回来  -我饿了
- We'll get him as soon as we're settled, okay? - I'm hungry.
妈妈把东西放好
Let mommy get situated,
就给你弄碗热麦片粥  好吗
then I'll make you a bowl of hot cereal, okay?
好吧
Okay.
过来
Come here.
亲爱的  你说过我们走之前
Honey, you said you were gonna wash the dishes
你会把餐具洗了
before we left.
我们走之前你整理床铺了吗
Didn't you make the bed before we left?
有人还睡过我们的床
Someone's been sleeping in our bed.
有人也睡过我的床
Someone's been sleeping in my bed, too,
而且他还在床上
and he's still there.
什么  宝贝  去我们房间待着
What? Baby, go wait in our room.
他睡着了吗
Is he asleep?
好呀
Oh, yeah!
正如我所说
That's what I'm talking about.
亲爱的  你一定要这么大声吗
Darling, must you talk so loud?
有人才刚起床
Some of us are still waking up.
什么事情能让你这么兴奋
What's all the excitement about?
只有《纽约莱杰报》
Only the "New York Ledger's"
评出的年度黄金单身汉名单
annual ten most eligible bachelor's list,
-猜猜谁榜上有名  -谁
- and guess who's on it. - Who?
不知道  不过他肯定是
I don't know, but he must be the president of
-帅哥中的帅哥  -排名第九
- the really-good-looking club. - Huh. Ranked number 9.
去年不是排名第七吗
Weren't you number 7 last year?
没错  还得感谢您
Yes, and thank you
再次指出我的缺点  母亲大人
for pointing out my shortcomings once again, mother.
我该做的嘛
Ah, that's my job.
幸运的是  我没朋友会看报纸杂志
Luckily all my friends are beyond print media.
有什么让你难堪的
What about this is embarrassing?
没什么  这关系到一个梦想
Nothing. It's the secret dream of every 16 year old
所有16岁的少女都梦想着老爸是
to have their father crowned one of the most available
-年度黄金单身汉  -如此说来
- hotties of the year. - Well, according to this,
你爸可能就榜上无名了
Your father may not be on the market.
-你没看简介吗  -没呢
- You didn't read the blurb here? - Mnh-mnh.
"尽管理查德・卡塞尔仍宣称单身
"Though claiming to be single,
但有消息称
Richard Castle is rumored to be
他和纽约警局凯特・贝克特探长
romantically involved with NYPD
-在恋爱中"  -什么
- detective kate beckett"... - What?!
"即妮基・希特的灵感女神"
"The inspiration for Nikki Heat,
"他最近一本畅销书的女主角
"the heroine of his latest best-selling novel.
现排名第九  也许明年不会上榜
Bachelor number 9 may not be eligible for next year's list."
什么  他们哪儿来的消息
What? Where did they get that?
等等  让我看看
Wait. Let me see.
在采访中我从来没说过这种话
I didn't say anything like that in my interview.
贝克特探长不会喜欢这个的
Detective Beckett is not going to love this.
也许她会一笑而过
Well, maybe she'll just laugh it off.
作为一个整天被女人包围的男人
How is it, for a man who is surrounded by women,
你对女人怎么就毫无了解呢
that you know so little about us?
说曹操  曹操到
Speak of the devil.
她打电话来要么是有命案
Okay, either beckett's calling because there's a dead body
-要么她已经读过报道了  -祈祷是命案吧
- or because she read the article. - Pray for murder.
早上好啊
Good morning.
命案  我没事了
Dead body. I'm good.
除了保姆  还有谁能进来
No one else had access to it, your maid...
-没有  -或其他可疑的人呢
-No. - Or anything like that?
你女儿的学校  他们知道...
Your daughter's school, they knew about...
他们知道你们出城了吗
They knew about you guys going out of town?
怎么了
What?
什么怎么了
What, what?
查到什么
So what have we got?
你的猜测跟我的检查结果一样
Your guess is as good as mine.
无名氏  无身份证
John Doe, no I.D.
死亡时间大约在昨晚9点
Approximate time of death is between 9:00 last night
到今天凌晨1点之间
1:00 this morning.
全家人度假回来发现死者
The family found him after returning from vacation.
可以说  死者住得挺乐呵
Apparently he made himself quite at home.
-怎么说  -我们发现
- How so? - Well, we found
他在冰箱里存有食物
his food in the fridge,
浴室里放了洗浴用品
toiletries in the bathroom,
甚至干衣机里还有衣服
even some of his clothes in the dryer.
现实中的金发姑娘[金发姑娘与熊的童话]
A real-life goldilocks.
的确  看起来尽管
Mm-hmm. It looks as though he
-他睡过父母的床  -当然
- even slept in the parents' bed. - Well, of course.
父母的床太硬
That one was too hard,
而熊宝宝的床正合适
and baby bear's bed was just right.
-看来他挣扎过  -挣扎无效
- Looks like he struggled. - Unsuccessfully.
这里  看到吗  注射器留下的针眼
Here. You see that? It's a needle mark from a syringe.
很可能因被注射某种药物
Probably was injected with something
致使他的心脏停止跳动
that stopped his heart.
我会做毒理测试
I'll run toxicology.
一旦确定死亡原因
As soon as I can pinpoint a C.O.D.,
-就打给你们  -很好  谢谢
- I'll give you a call. - Great. Thank you.
知道谁会用注射器杀人吗
You know who kills with syringes?
疯子医生  低成本电影里的纳粹
Mad doctors and b-movie nazis.
-为什么不用枪  -枪声太大
- Why not just use a gun? - Guns are loud.
我见过有人住无主空屋
I've seen squatters in abandoned buildings,
但没见过这样的
but nothing like this.
还有人溜进来用注射器杀人
And then someone sneaks in and kills him with a needle.
-真奇怪  -是啊  戴森夫妇怎么样
- Weird. - Mm-hmm. How are the Dysons doing?
父母两人都很震惊
Mom and dad are pretty shaken up.
女儿还不知道怎么回事
Little girl doesn't really know what's going on.
有人知道他们出城了吗
Did anyone know they were leaving town?
只有同事  女儿的学校方面
Uh, just people from work, daughter's school,
-就这些人  还在查  -过来看
- stuff like that. We're running it down. - Hey, check this out.
戴森夫妇在厨房里发现了这个
Dysons found this in the kitchen,
说不是他们的
said it's not theirs.
是这里的照片
This is here.
是啊  奇怪吧
Yeah, weird, huh?
为什么要拍照呢
Why would he take pictures?
这样他才能物归原位
So he could put everything back the way he found it.
他希望没人发现他来过
He was hoping nobody would know that he was here.
尽管他尽力了  还是差点儿
Almost as though he was hiding.
让技术部门查查记忆卡
All right, have a tech pull the memory card.
看看通过被删照片
See if any of the deleted photos
能否查出他的身份
can tell us who he is.
-她会杀了他  -他死定了
- Ooh, she is gonna kill him. - He's dead.
卡塞尔  是真的吗  你会最终退出榜单吗
So, Castle, is it true? Are you finally off the market?
你们俩  如果谁走漏半点风声
You guys, if either of you breathe a word of this...
我发誓  我会让你们付出代价的
I swear, I will make you pay.
蒙哥马利问最新进度
Montgomery's up to speed.
戴森夫妇公司  孩子学校
Anything back from the Dysons' workplace or the kid's...
-有消息吗  -知道他们出城的人
- school? - I ran background checks
我已经都查过了
on everyone who knew the family was gonna be out of town.
目前为止都无嫌疑
So far everyone's come back clean,
不过会继续查的
but I'm gonna keep digging.
查访的情况呢
Anything on the canvass?
一无所获  这栋楼没有门卫
A whole lot of nothing. No doorman on the building.
邻居们没有发现任何异常
None of the Dyson's neighbors noticed anything
仅仅是感到震惊
out of the ordinary.
恐怖  我那地方住了八年了
Shocker. I've lived in my spot eight years.
一个邻居我也认不出
I couldn't pick my neighbors out of a lineup.
曼哈顿就是这样啊
Well, that's Manhattan for you.
除非有直接关系  否则彼此都不认识
Nobody notices anything unless it affects them directly.
-除非上报  -失陪  贝克特
- Unless it's in the paper. - Excuse me. Beckett.
好  好  很好
Great. Okay, good.
通过死者指纹查到了
Got a hit off of John Doe's fingerprints.
道格拉斯・比谢普  在资料库里
Douglass Bishop. He's in the system.
道格拉斯・比谢普
Douglass Bishop...
十年前被捕过一次
Arrested once ten years ago--
轻微罪  酒后闹事
misdemeanor drunk and disorderly.
后免于起诉  除此之外  算身家清白
Charges were dropped. Besides that, he's clean.
好吧  通知亲属
All right, find the next of kin.
他们认完尸  也许能告诉我们
After they I.D. the body, maybe they can tell us
他到底在那间公寓干什么
what the hell he was doing in that apartment.
从实验室得到结果
I got the results back from the lab.
他被注射了一种麻醉剂  氯胺酮
He was injected with an anesthetic--Ketamine.
K粉[毒品]  他死于俱乐部常用毒品
Special "K"? He was killed by a club drug?
那种剂量并不致死
Not in this dose.
给死者注射毒品的人  可不是让他兴奋
Whoever shot up Mr. Bishop was not looking to get him high.
那剂量足能灭了一匹马
Gave him enough to put down a horse.
受害人的姐姐来了
The victim's sister is here.
我是贝克特探长
I'm detective Beckett.
感谢你们过来
Thank you so much for coming down.
真的是他吗
Is--is that him?
真是道格吗
Is that Doug?
所以警方需要你来确认
That's what we'll need you to verify.
这根本不合理
None of this makes any sense.
为什么道格要住别人家呢
I mean, why would Doug be living in these people's apartment?
他在霍博肯市有自己的房子
He's got his own place out in Hoboken.
有没有可能是你弟弟惹祸上身
Is it possible that your brother was in trouble,
因此在躲避什么人
that he was hiding from someone?
不会  道格是个受欢迎的人
No. Everybody loved Doug.
他有没有欠人钱
Did he owe anybody money
或者经济困难
or have any financial problems?
据我所知  没有
Not that I know of.
他在旅行社的工作时间
I-I mean, his hours at the travel agency
是缩短了
got cut back,
但他还能过得去
But he was getting by.
旅行社
Travel agency.
也许正因此他会知道
Maybe that's how he knew the
-戴森一家出城了  -但如果他遇到麻烦
- Dysons were out of town. - But if he were in trouble,
他可以动用潜水资金
he would've raided his scuba fund.
他总是说  如果哪天时候到了
He was always saying that someday when his ship came in,
就在牙买加给自己开...
he was gonna get himself a little--
-一间潜水用品小店  -道格正为此攒钱
- a little scuba shop down in Jamaica. - Doug was saving up for it.
每个月都把一部分工资
He would put a portion of his paycheck
存入一个账户
in an account every month.
最后一次见你弟弟是什么时候
When was the last time you saw your brother?
上次的假期派对
Not since the holiday party.
道格的旅行社在机场办的
Doug's agency threw it out by the airport,
是斯坦工作的机场  所以我们都去了
which is where Stan works, so we all went.
人总是无法预料这种事
You just never think something like this is gonna happen.
所以安排不了时间
So you don't make time.
好  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
旅行社有点问题
That was the travel agency.
如果道格在躲什么人
If Foug was hiding from someone,
说明他工作不顺
he wasn't doing a very good job.
但昨天之前  他每天都上班
Apparently he hasn't missed a day of work until yesterday.
戴森家的旅行呢
What about the Dysons' trip?
经手的是别家旅行社
They booked it through a different agency.
-潜水资金  -没动过
- The scuba fund? - Didn't touch it.
所以他不是躲人  也没欠债
So he wasn't in hiding, he didn't owe anybody any money
而他又无法得知
and he had no discernible way
-戴森一家何时出城  -贝克特
- of knowing when the Dysons would be out of town. - Hey, Beckett.
电脑高手把死者相机记忆卡里
The geeks managed to pull the deleted photos from
被删掉的照片复原了  想看吗
our squatter's memory card. Care to take a look?
柜台  橱柜内部的照片
Stuff on counters, inside cabinets.
不是在戴森家
That's not the Dysons' place.
他以前也做过  只是在别人家
He's done this before, but in other apartments.
也许他只为求刺激
Maybe he does it for the thrill.
也许有人发现了  火大了
Maybe someone found out and got mad.
但死者还是得知道屋主何时出门
But he'd still have to know when they were away.
除非道格・比谢普并非借住人
Unless Doug Bishop isn't our squatter.
那个肯定不是道格・比谢普
That's definitely not Doug Bishop.
他是谁
Who is he?
可能就是凶手
He's probably our killer.
什么变态
What kind of psycho pads
会给和凶器合影呢
Takes pictures of himself and his murder weapons?
有些凶手要留纪念品
Some killers keep trophies.
为了自保  他的确把照片删了
In his defense, he did delete these photos.
加消音器的45口径手枪  他要干什么
45 with a silencer. Wonder what he had lined up for this?
干坏事
Nothing good.
鉴证组套取了相机和
Has C.S.U. Pulled the prints off of the camera
私人物品上的指纹吗
and personal effects?
是的  但不是道格・比谢普
Yeah, they don't match Doug Bishop
在资料库也找不到
and they're not in the system.
即他没有案底
Which means he doesn't have a record.
那  如果道格不是借住
Well, if Doug wasn't our squatter,
去戴森家里干什么
What was he doing in the Dysons' apartment?
他肯定认识那个借住人
He had to have known the squatter somehow.
若这个借住者思维缜密
If this squatter was so meticulous
比如要物归原处
Taking about putting things back,
又怎会留下这个线索呢
why'd he leave all this for us to find?
没错  这说不通
You're right. It--it makes no sense.
什么  不杜撰些戏剧性理论吗
What? No grand theatrical theory to spin for us?
说实话  没有
Honestly, I-I got nothing.
更重要的是  我们没有任何线索
More importantly, we don't have any prints or leads.
怎么揪出这个小鬼
How are we gonna catch a ghost?
找出他是怎样出入的
By finding out how he haunts.
如果查处借住人是怎样知道
If we can figure out how the squatter knew
目标要出城
His marks were out of town,
找出他与借住地的关系
find something that connects him to the other places that he stayed,
也许就能缩小范围
Then maybe we can narrow down the field.
我们继续朝这个方向查
We'll keep going through these.
顺利的话  就能发现线索
With any luck, we'll find something that can tell us
-查到其他屋主  -很好  谢谢
- whose apartments these are. - Okay, great. Thank you.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
-查查昨晚比赛谁赢了  -我们
- I'm looking to see who won the game last night.  - Oh, we won.
你知道我说的是什么比赛吗
Do you even know what game I'm talking about?
当然知道  年度重大比赛
Sure I do. The big game.
好了  卡塞尔  怎么回事
Okay, Castle. What's going on?
贝克特  看看这个
Yo, Beckett. Check this out.
他给别人的药箱拍了照
He took a picture of the inside of someone's medicine cabinet.
处方药瓶上的名字几乎看得清
You can almost make out the name on these prescription bottles.
让技术部看看这个
Have I.S. Take a look at it,
看他们能否增加清晰度
See if they can enhance the photo.
老天
Oh, god.
他翻遍了我的药箱
He went through my medicine cabinet?
请别说他还看了我的日记
Please tell me he didn't go through my diary.
我们不确定  兰福特女士
Oh, we're not sure, Ms. Langford.
-你确定不认识他  -是的  很确定
- Are you sure you don't recognize him?  - Yeah, I'm positive.
-你也不认识戴森一家  -不认识
- And you don't know the Dysons?  - No.
只有我母亲知道我出城了
The only person that knew I was even out of town was my mother.
大家都以为我请病假了
Everyone else thought I was on sick leave.
你不会告诉我老板这个吧  是吗
You won't tell my boss that, will you?
当你回来时  有没有发现异常
Did you notice anything unusual when you returned?
我终于懂了
Oh, that totally explains it.
怎么了
What?
我的水龙头  几个星期了
My faucet. For weeks,
一直催楼管来修漏水的水龙头
I've been asking my superTo fix my leaky faucet,
但他总不来
but he never came.
当我回来后  修好了
And then when I got back, it was fixed.
我就以为他终于来了
So I just assumed that he finally did it,
但过后  我在楼梯上看到他
But then later, when I saw him on the stairs,
他根本不知道我在讲什么
He didn't even know what I was talking about.
借住的家伙修好了你的水龙头
The squatter fixed your sink?
没错  冰箱里还有一瓶
Yeah. And there was this bottle of, um,
奇怪的草莓香槟
Like weird strawberry champagne in the fridge.
我还以为是走前的派对后
And I just assumed that one of my friends had left it
某个朋友留下的  但是
During a dinner party I had before I left, but...
我的朋友都不会买这样
None of my friends would've bought such a--
-廉价的酒  -正是
- Cheap bottle of booze.  - Exactly.
他干了修理活
So he makes repairs,
还给房主礼物  他是挺有风度的
Leaves hostess gifts-- he's the gentleman squatter.
他杀了人  所以别把他说成
Who killed a man, so don't make him out to be
年度贵客
The houseguest of the year.
感谢你过来一趟  兰福特女士
Thank you for coming in, Ms. Langford.
顺便说一下
By the way,
报纸上的照片可别介意
That photo in the paper, did you no justice.
真人帅过上镜
You're much better looking in person.
报纸上有你的照片
There's a picture of you in the paper?
那你就是探长女友
So are you the detective girlfriend?
很抱歉  你刚说什么
I'm sorry, the what?
他真是理想对象
He... is such a catch.
别
Don't.
给我看看  马上
Show me. Now.
-"在恋爱中"  -"据传"
- "Romantically involved"?  - "Rumored to be."
你说什么了
What did you tell them?
什么也没有  我干嘛要这样做
Nothing! Why would I do that?
你知道这多影响我的声誉吗
Do you have any idea what this does to my reputation?
你的声誉  那我的呢
Your reputation? What about my reputation?
我也很生气  我们是一条船上的
I am just as upset as you are. I'm on your team.
卑鄙的媒体
This is shoddy journalism,
我就差没取消订阅了
And I am two seconds away from canceling my subscription.
-我的订阅  -你有没有想过
- My subscription.  - Do you have
做一名女警有多难吗
any idea how hard it is to be a female cop?
我最不希望的就是  你爆猛料给
The last thing I need is for you to give them more ammo to
是的  请接《纽约莱杰报》
Yes, the "New York ledger," Please.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
兰福特说只有她母亲知道
Langford said that the only person
她去旅游了  但真实情况并非如此
Who knew she was on vacation was her mother, but that's not true.
如果真是装病
If she was actually pretending to be sick,
她可不想让报纸在门前
The last thing she'd want is newspapers piling up
堆成小山
at her front door.
她暂停订报了
She had the papers held.
是的  请接订阅部
Yes, your subscription department, please.
了解假期暂停订阅信息的人
Anyone with access to vacation hold information would know
就知道谁出门  还有去多久
Exactly who's out of town and for exactly how long.
是的  我想确认假期暂停订阅的
Yes, I would like to verify vacation hold information
两位客户的资料
On two of your subscribers, please.
我是谁  我
Who am I? I... i...
-有时忘了自己不是警察  -我没忘
- I sometimes forget I'm not actually a cop. - I don't.
你好  纽约警局凯特・贝克特探长
Hi. This is detective Kate Beckett with the NYPD.
请找你们主管接电话
I'd like to speak with your supervisor, please.
我不敢说他是否眼熟
I can't really say he looks familiar,
你们得明白  我们有几百名员工
But you gotta understand, we have hundreds of employees.
那有多少人有权限
Well, how many of them had access
了解假期暂停订阅信息
to vacation hold information?
有十几人负责订阅事宜
Well, you got about a dozen in subscriptions,
收费的也有些个
Another handful in billing,
当然还有送报员
And, of course, the newspaperboys themselves.
我要看看名单
I'm gonna need to see a list of their names.
可以  跟我来
Sure. Follow me.
达娜
Donna.
理查德  你来这里做什么
Richard. What are you doing here?
不是因为排第九生气了吧
Uh, you're not mad about number 9, are you?
我跟编辑说了  还把你排第七的
I told my editor to keep you at 7.
不  不是那个  我不太在意
No, no, it's not that. I don't care about that... much.
只是  你说我和贝克特探长在恋爱
It's--I just--why did you say I was dating detective beckett?
我猜的
Oh. Well, I just assumed.
你采访时一直在谈论她
You kept bringing her up during the interview.
不  我没有
No, I didn't.
你有  你一直在谈论她
Sure you did. You went on and on about her.
贝克特说最好笑是  那方面她最好
"Beckett said the funniest this, she's the best that."
真的吗  我那样吗
Really? I did that?
去年  你光聊自己
Last year all you did was talk about yourself.
达娜  我完完全全是单身
Well, Donna, I am very, very single.
真的吗  既然你们没恋爱
Really? Because if you aren't involved,
排第三的未婚佳丽今早还问到你
Bachelorette number 3 asked about you this morning.
你见到她了吗  没有
Did you see her? No?
你是不是连报纸的第一页都不看完
Or are you one of those people who never goes below the fold?
怎么会  我会看完第一页
Oh, I go below the fold.
只是  最近忙着写
It's just, lately I've been very busy
《妮基・希特》系列的第二本
With my second nikki heat novel,
-就没有...老天  -阿曼达・利文斯顿
- and I n-oh, my god.  - Amanda Livingston.
要她的号码吗  她可想要你的
So do you want her number? 'Cause she wants yours.
找到一个符合的
Hey, we got a match.
米齐・卡尔森  送报员
Mickey Carlson, delivery boy.
戴森和米歇尔・兰福特
Both the Dysons and Michele Langford
-都是他的客户  -送报员  收到
- are on his route. - Delivery boy. Knew it.
不管怎样  他今早没来
Anyway, he didn't show this morning.
其他送报员帮他顶班
Another carrier had to cover.
申请表上没有地址
You know, there's no address on this application.
-档案上还存有吗  -没有
- Do you have one on file?  - Nah.
他从没给过  我现在知道原因了
He never gave us one, and now I know why.
所以是  明天发薪水
It says there that payday is tomorrow.
是直接打到他账上  还是
Does Mickey do direct deposit or does--
他来拿支票的  时间分毫不差
Pick up his own check? Like clockwork.
工资表上午10点出
Payroll comes in at 10:00 in the morning,
米齐10点零1分出现
Mickey's here at 10:01.
送报员
A delivery boy
居然有消音器和麻醉针剂
With a silencer and syringes full of ketamine?
不管他到底是干什么的
His job's just a front
这工作只是幌子
For whatever business he's really in.
这是他的客户中暂停订阅的名单
Here's a list of all of the vacation holds on his route.
他可能借住在任何一家
He could be squatting at any one of them.
他身上有枪  确保你们组高度戒备
He's armed, so make sure your teams use extreme caution.
卡塞尔和我在报社埋伏  以防他出现
Castle and I will set up at the paper in case he shows.
如果他在  肯定会抓住他
If he's out there, we'll find him.
真讽刺
It's ironic, you know.
申请暂定订阅不正是为防贼入室
People put in vacation holds to avoid break-ins.
这个反讽用的好
Good use of irony.
-报社里谁是你的朋友  -达娜・文森斯
- So who's your friend at the paper?  - Oh, Donna Vncennes?
就是她写的  我们在恋爱
Mm-hmm. She's the one who wrote the blurb about us.
-没有"我们"  -我知道
- There is no "Us."  - I know that.
-你解释给她听了吗  -是的
- Did you tell her that?  - Yes, I did,
真是有效  我颇有收获
Which worked out, actually, really well for me.
因为结果是
As it turns out,
排名第三的未婚佳丽
Most eligible bachelorette numero tres--
对我很兴趣  想见我
Very interested in meeting me.
一旦娱记知道她和我约会
Once the info-tainers get ahold of her with me,
就会忘了你我的流言
They're gonna forget all about you and I.
标题都能猜得到
I can just see the headlines now--
金童玉女共进晚餐
"9 meets 3 at dinner for 2."
信不信由你
Believe it or not,
纽约城的许多女人
There's a lot of women in this town
都想和我谈恋爱
Who like the idea of being romantically linked to me.
我没有生活了
I have no life.
不  比谢普先生才死了
No, Mr. Bishop has no life.
所以才躺在这里
That's why he's on my table.
我得约会
I need a date.
什么
What?
约会  男人  男士
A date. A... guy. A... man.
你老想给我拉红线
You're always trying to set me up with people.
所以我来了  我去  有什么介绍
So here I am. I'm game. What do you got?
好吧
Okay.
受什么刺激了
What's gotten into you?
工作太累了  我想做的就是回家
I get so wrapped up in work, all I want to do is go home
可是家里很安静  我现在厌倦了安静
where it's quiet, and I'm so tired of quiet.
我想要  喧闹
I want... loud.
好吧
Okay.
给你个完美处方
I have the perfect prescription for you.
布拉德克
Bradekker?
不是  宝贝  是布拉德・戴克
No, no, baby. That's Brad Dekker.
之前想介绍给你的消防员
That firefighter I wanted to set you up with.
-他帅吗  -他可是去年
- Is he cute?  - He was Mr. July
纽约消防员挂历上的七月先生
In last year's New York firefighters calendar.
七月啊
July.
最帅的才能放在夏季
They always put the really hot ones in the summer months.
没错
Exactly.
那我们约8点  怎样
Well, then should we say around 8:00?
好的  我也是
All right. Me, too.
晚安  阿曼达
Good night, Amanda.
抱歉  错过晚饭了
Ahh. Sorry I missed dinner.
如果你饿的话  还有乳蛋饼
There's quiche if you're hungry.
好极了  很美味
Sweet. Or savory, actually.
你今天过得怎么样
So... how was your day?
说实话今天过得还真不错
I had a truly great day.
上课中被叫到
I got pulled out of class
副校长办公室了
And called to the vice principal's office.
-为什么 她想干什么  -不就是你
- Why? What did she want? - You.
-这是她的号码  -她的号码
- Here's her number. - Her number?
我的德语老师  芙劳琳・索内伯格
Oh, and my German teacher, Fraulein Sonnenberg,
让我转告你一句德语
Wanted me to tell you, auf deutsch,
"你很有魅力"
"Du hast sex-appeal."
再过两年  她就能按长者菜单[有折扣]点餐了
She's two years from ordering off the senior menu,
不过这是她的号
But here's her number, too.
芙劳琳・索内伯格
Fraulein Sonnenberg?
嫌她太老吗
Too old?
这样吧  我朋友斯隆怎么样
That's okay 'cause my friend Sloan
认为你是"真命天子"
Thinks you're "Real choice."
她今年17岁
She's 17,
不过还有三个月就到法定年龄了
but she'll be legal in 3 months.
你可以来个大小通吃
Hey. Maybe we could double.
你现在有些讨厌我了吗
Oh, you hate me a little bit right now, don't you?
是有点点  贝克特怎么说
Just a little. What did Beckett say?
她应该没什么意见吧
Oh, I'm sure she'll be fine with it.
甚至可能感到荣幸
Maybe even a little flattered.
感到荣幸
Flattered?
我还打算...吃些呢
I was gonna... Eat that.
10点15了  米齐还没出现
10:15. Mickey's a no-show.
耐心点  卡塞尔
Patience, Castle.
你听过德拉贡餐厅吗
Hey, have you ever heard of Drago?
莱杰报评出的十大最浪漫餐厅之一
It's on the "Ledger's" Top ten most romantic restaurants.
相当贵  几乎订不到位子
It's pricey and impossible to get a table,
除非你认识人
Unless you know someone.
怎么了
Why?
我只是想找一个好点的地方
Just looking for a place to go.
-去约会吗  -是  去约会
- What, like on a date? - Yes, on a date.
-你看起来很吃惊  -怎么会
- Why do you sound so surprised? - No, I--
我只是
No, I just, uh,
没想过你是会去德拉贡的人
never figured you for a Drago kind of girl.
是吗
Really?
那你认为我是什么样的人  卡塞尔
And what kind of a girl do you figure me for, Castle?
我只是
I... it--
目标出现
Oh! There's your boy.
米齐・卡尔森  我是
Mickey Carlson, I'm...
站住
Hey!
米齐・卡尔森
Mickey Carlson...
你因涉嫌谋杀道格拉斯・比谢普被捕
You're under arrest  for the murder of Douglass Bishop.
这是你谋杀道格・比谢普的镉试剂
This is the cadimium that you used to kill Doug Bishop.
不  不  这不是我的
Whoa. No, no, that's not mine.
你很聪明  没用枪杀他
Pretty smart not using the gun, Mickey.
-那样的话会很麻烦  -这不是我的枪
-That would've been too messy. - That's not my gun.
我发誓  我没杀人
Look, I didn't kill anybody. I swear.
我没犯法  我只是借住在那里
I'm not a criminal, all right? I was just squatting there.
从法律上说  借住也是犯罪
Well, technically, squatting is a crime.
是的  与人无害的犯罪
Yeah, a victimless crime,
我挺有礼貌的
especially the way I do it.
如果道格・比谢普不是你杀的
If you didn't kill Doug Bishop,
他怎么会死在戴森家
then how did he end up dead in the Dysons' apartment?
肯定是住梅特兰家的家伙
The guy from the Maitlands' apartment must have killed him.
梅特兰家
And who are the Maitlands?
在去戴森家前
The people whose apartment
我借住的那家
I stayed in before the Dysons.
现在从头开始交待
Okay, why don't you start from the beginning,
一件事也别落下
And take us through it from there?
梅特兰家暂停订报一周
The Maitlands put a week hold on their paper,
我琢磨着  他们住在东27街
which I was psyched about, 'cause they live on east 27th,
那里有许多超赞的印度餐馆
which has amazing indian restaurants.
所以我撬了锁  就开始拍照
So I pick the lock, I start taking pictures
走的时候才能物归原位
so I can return everything to its original state.
拍照的时候
I'm taking pictures
看到桌子上放着这些注射器
when I find these syringes on the table.
觉得怪怪的  但是想
Kinda weird, but I'm thinking,
也许梅特兰家有人
maybe one of the Maitlands
得了糖尿病什么的
must be diabetic or something, right?
我就接着拍照  但突然想到
So I keep going. Then bam--it hits me.
床上怎么会有加了消音器的枪
What's a gun with a silencer doing out on the bed?
接下来
And next to it,
-我又发现好多工具  -工具
- I see all this gear. - Gear?
登山装备
Mountain climbing equipment.
我想  我看到太多了
At this point, I seen enough.
就打算离开
I decide to get outta there.
我拿起东西  准备走人
But just as I'm grabbing my stuff,
我听见门开了
I hear the door unlock.
抓紧时间  躲进了衣橱
And I barely reach the closet in time.
从缝隙中看见他们  有三个人
I could see 'em through the slats. It was three of 'em.
他是其中一个  大众脸
It was, uh, this guy, a plain-looking dude
还有个凶神面煞的杂种
And tough-looking S.O.B.
他脸上有一道新月形的疤痕
Man, he had a scar on his face looked like a crescent moon.
新月形
A crescent moon?
我知道有些夸张
I know, right? It's crazy.
管他呢  接着他们走进里屋
Anyway, they head into the back.
我抓紧这个空当
I take the opportunity
拿着我的东西  离开了那个鬼地方
to grab my stuff and get the hell outta there.
就到了戴森家
I end up at the Dysons'.
把东西放下  我才缓过来
Take a load off, I get comfortable,
不知什么时候  前门打开了
when outta nowhere, the front door opens,
他和他朋友进来了
and him and his friend come in.
哪个  有新月疤的吗
Who, crescent-moon scar face?
不是  是那个大众脸
No, the--the other guy. The plain one.
他们逮着我了
They grab me and demand
让我把手机还给他们
that I give them their phone back.
手机
Their phone?
你走的时候顺手牵羊了
Are you making this up as you go?
不  是这样的  我走的时候
No, no, no, see, in my race to get out of the Maitlands',
不小心拿了他们中某人的外套
I must have grabbed one of their jackets,
有个手机在里面
which had their phone in it,
但不知道他们怎么找到我的
but I don't know how they knew.
最新的手机有GPS
Newer phones have GPS.
他们可以在网上追踪
They could track it on the web.
我解释说我不是故意的  要还手机
Well, I didn't want their phone and I tried to give it back.
但是他们拿出一支注射器
The guy pulls out a syringe
正准备给我注射
and is ready to stab me with it.
真得感谢道格
But thank god for Doug. Oh, man.
他说  "我可不想成为杀人犯"
Doug says, "I didn't sign up for murder."
他们便开始争论
Then they start arguing,
接着拿注射器的家伙说
and then the syringe guy says,
"这里有三毫升  他看到太多了 "
"We've got 3 mil on the line. He's seen too much."
接下来他们就打起来了
Next thing I know, they're fighting.
我就趁机逃跑了
So I ran outta there.
我只想说
I'm just saying,
真是个不错的故事  你觉得呢
it's a really good story. Come on.
一群奇怪的坏蛋  新月形疤痕
mysterious bad guys, crescent-shaped scars,
躲在衣橱里
hiding in a closet?
听起来像小说  因为可能就是小说
It sounds like fiction because it probably is.
太糟糕了  他是个不错的人
Well, that's too bad. He's a nice guy.
杰弗里・达默[食人连环杀手]也不错
So was Jeffrey Dahmer.
从未停止食人事业
Didn't stop him from eating people.
梅特兰家查得如何
Where are we on these Maitlands?
他们在一艘游轮上
They're on a cruise ship,
已经让游轮安保部门去找他们了
but we're getting the ship's security to track 'em down right now.
尽快找到他们
All right, have 'em track faster.
需要他们的许可才能进去看看
I need their permission to get into the place.
难道不能申请搜查令吗
Can't we just get a warrant?
因为杀人嫌犯的片面之词吗
On the word of a possible murder suspect?
算不得正当理由
Not exactly probable cause.
不过一旦证实卡尔森先生是编故事
But once we disprove Mr. Carlson's story,
我们会以谋杀罪起诉他
We'll be able to press charges for murder.
你好  我是贝克特
Beckett.
你好  布拉德
Oh, hi, Brad.
不  不  不算仓促
Uh, uh, no. No, no, no, it's not too last-minute.
事实上  我今晚没安排
Actually, my plans for tonight just fell through.
布拉德是谁
Who's Brad?
应该是蕾妮的朋友
Mm. Must be Lanie's friend.
你们认识吗
You know him?
是  见过一次  挺优秀的
Yeah, met him once. Good guy.
消防员
Fireman.
上过纽约消防局日历  外表英俊
He was in the F.D.N.Y. Calendar. Chiseled good looks.
腹肌相当结实
Rock-hard abs.
据说  有一次救火
Oh, and get this-- once during a fire,
他救完一家人后
after saving the parents and the kids,
为了救小狗  他又冲进火里
he went back in for the puppies.
那到时见
See you then.
她是在玩头发吗
Did she just flip her hair?
老兄  你在听我说吗  小狗
I'm telling you, bro, puppies...
-他每次都会救  -小狗
- Gets 'em every time. - Puppies.
你好  是梅特兰先生吗
Yes, Mr. Maitland?
怎么了
What?
-你竟然在笑  -那又怎样
- You're smiling. - So?
再见  找到梅特兰一家了
Good-bye. Hey. We got the Maitlands.
可以进屋查探了
We're good to enter.
他们正在联系楼管
They're calling the super right now.
好的  行动吧
Okay, let's go.
先生  请止步
Stay out here, please sir.
-我们去里屋  -好的
- We'll check the back. - Okay.
好吧  我们期待吧
Well, surprise, surprise.
没东西能证实米齐的话
Nothing here to verify Mickey's version.
来看看这里
Oh, wow. Look at this.
发现什么了吗
Did you find something?
是的  老式的餐馆升降机
Yeah, it's an old-fashioned dumbwaiter.
现在再看不到这些东西了
You don't see these around anymore.
真有才
Genius, too.
梅特兰家把它改成了
The Maitlands have converted it
可藏式音响组合橱
Into a hidden stereo component cupboard.
我敢说一定有个遥控器
I bet they have an R.F. Remote somewhere.
我们不是来参观的  卡塞尔
We're not here to admire the place, Castle.
怎么能不参观啊  看看这屋子
How can you not? I mean, look at this place.
这间是19世纪末的战前公寓
This apartment is prewar, late 1800s.
看看这墙裙
Oh, you see this molding?
是原木造的  太华丽了
That is the original wood. Gorgeous.
我敢说  浴室肯定是大理石墙板
I bet the bathrooms have marble wainscoting.
你真是个都市型男
You're such a metrosexual.
总好过日历型男[还有娘娘腔的意思]
Yes. Well, better than being a pinup boy.
你听说了
So you heard?
卡塞尔  他是上过日历
And it's pinup man, Castle.
英俊.....的男人
Pinup... man.
好吧  和你的消防员玩得开心
Yes. Well, have fun with your hose jockey
而我将要和纽约排名第三的
Whilst I go out with New York's
单身佳丽约会去
Most eligible bachelorette number 3.
我倒是觉得她有些委屈
Oh, I guess that means she must be slumming it,
她排第三  而你才第九
Her being number 3 and you being a lowly number 9.
那你排多少呢
What number were you again?
没有异况
Place is clear.
没有枪  没有氯胺酮
No gun, no ketamine,
也没什么登山工具
no mountain climbing equipment.
什么都没有
There is nothing here.
不  那里有
Yes, there is.
冷藏箱  19世纪末期使用
An icebox, circa late 1800s.
看见没
You see, before the invention
在家用电冰箱发明之前
Of modern household refrigeration,
人们把易坏物品放到这个有冰块的
People used to keep their perishable items in a box
箱子保鲜
That held ice.
所以这是一个  冷藏箱
Hence--an icebox.
我说了这不是参观日  卡塞尔
It's not an open house, Castle.
梅特兰家真是太有才了
Oh, the Maitlands were very clever.
他们把这里改成碗橱了
They converted this into a cupboard.
刚好靠近电冰箱
Meanwhile, it's right next to their fridge--aah!
太出乎意料了
I did not expect that.
新月型的疤痕
Crescent-shaped scar.
看来米齐的故事有些可信了
Looks like there was some truth to Mickey's tale after all.
他叫安东・弗朗西斯
His name is Anton Francis.
这位弗朗西斯先生
Mr. Francis here,
人完全可以貌相
not wanting to waste such a sinister looking scar
真是无恶不作
decide to round out the stereotype
他已数案在身
with a laundry list of criminal activity,
包括入室偷窃
including fencing stolen property,
多起持枪抢劫以及一起砸窗抢劫
stickups and a smash and grab.
-死亡时间呢  -大概是
- Do we have time of death? - Yes,
今天凌晨1点到4点间
between 1:00 and 4:00 a.m. this morning,
这就排除了米齐・卡尔森的作案可能
which rules out Mickey Carlson.
刚查证他昨晚在一间避难所过夜
We verified that he stayed in a homeless shelter last night.
如果米齐说的是真话
So if Mickey was telling us the truth,
那么道格和弗朗西斯
then Doug and Mr. Francis
很明显没预料到内讧
clearly got more than they bargained for.
所有的一切都是他们的同伙做的
All by the murderous hand of their partner--
即用氯胺酮杀死道格的人
the guy who killed Doug with the syringe--
-神秘的第三人  -找出安东的
- our mysteriou is 3rd man. - Let's get photos of
所有朋友和监狱室友的照片
all of Anton's known associates and former cell mates.
如果米齐看到
If Mickey saw his face,
他应该能认出来的
he should be able to I.D. him for us.
身家清白的道格拉斯・比谢普
So how does a man like Douglass Bishop--
是如何与惯犯
with no criminal record--
搞在一起的呢
get involved with hardened criminals?
很简单  他们需要他
Simple. They needed him.
我认为  案发时梅特兰一家的出城
It seemed convenient to me that the Maitlands were out of town
过于巧合  于是查了查
when all this went down, so I did some digging.
发现他们拿到的船票
Turns out that cruise they're on,
是在比赛中赢的
they won it in a contest.
而所谓的比赛根本不存在
Only there is no contest.
伪造的中奖函
A phony award letter?
是的  当他们拿到中奖函和船票
Yeah, when they got that and the tickets,
他们就想  馅饼不捡白不捡
they figured, why look a gift horse in the mouth.
猜猜船票哪来的
So guess where the tickets came from.
道格・比谢普的旅行社
Doug Bishop's travel agency.
船票只是为了骗
So the cruise was just a scam
梅特兰一家出城
to get the Maitlands out of town.
中奖函说游轮本周出发
The letter says that the cruise had to be this week.
-为何是本周  -为何是梅特兰一家
- Why this week? - And why the Maitlands?
除非这些坏家伙就是喜欢战前建筑物
Well, unless our bad guys are into prewar architecture,
那间公寓里没有值钱东西
there's really nothing in that apartment that's worth anything
除了那套音响组合
except for the audio/visual equipment,
-但还在呢  -为何要大费周张
- which was still there. - Why go through so much trouble
进入梅特兰家
to get in the Maitlands' apartment?
或许他们的目标不在梅特兰家
Maybe what they wanted wasn't in the Maitlands' apartment.
或许打劫对象是别家
Maybe they were gonna rob someone else,
只是需要从这里进去
But just needed access.
音响组合
The audio/visual equipment.
就是入口
Access.
梅特兰家在二楼
The Maitlands live on the second floor.
音响组合的正下方
Running perpendicular to them and whatever's below
是老式升降机通道
is the old dumbwaiter shaft.
在《风暴集结》我安排德里克・斯道姆
In "Gathering Storm," I had Derrick Storm
爬进升降机通道  以躲开捷克杀手
climb up the dumbwaiter shaft to bypass the Czech assassin
救出瑞士大使的女儿
in order to save the Swiss ambassador's daughter.
或许罪犯们是利用升降机
Maybe our bad guys are using the dumbwaiter
躲开下面的保安
to bypass the security of whatever's below them.
这也解释了为何会有绳索和登山装备
Which would explain the ropes and the climbing gear.
那么  梅特兰家楼下是什么呢
So what's below the Maitlands' apartment?
宠物店
A pet shop.
为何不来店里看一看它们
Why don't you come down and have a look at them?
城里的爬行动物  我这里选择最多
I have the largest selection of reptiles in the city.
只有我们店才有
They're my specialty.
很乐意
My pleasure.
好  谢谢  再见
Okay. Thank you. Bye-bye.
二位好  有什么能效劳的吗
Ah, how is it? Can I, uh, can I help you?
你确定没丢东西
And you're sure nothing was stolen?
是的  我说  有什么可偷的
Ya. I mean, what is there to steal?
升降机通道是最近被打开的
This dumbwaiter has been opened recently.
打开了吗
It was open?
米齐说  那三人说  有几百万保不住了
Mickey told us his attacker said there was millions at stake.
杜・普利先生  隔着墙是什么
Mr. Du Preez, What's on the other side of that wall?
第28大街  东区信托银行
28th STREET. EASTSIDE BANK AND TRUST.
银行抢劫
A bank heist.
看起来是计划打通后墙
It looks like the plan was to cut into the back wall
进入另一边的银行保险库
to get into the bank vault on the other side.
我们已通知银行经理  联调局
We called the bank manager, the FBI,
-但疑犯并没下手  -出了什么问题
- But our guys never made it that far. - What went wrong?
不知道  可能是因为贪婪  恐惧
We don't know. It could've been greed, panic.
好像是死者的同伙
It looks like our victims might have been betrayed
背叛了他
by their partner.
过去  拿了钱才会杀同伙
In the old days, you killed your partners after you got the money.
神秘的第三人有头绪吗
Any leads on this, uh, third man?
没有  给借住人看了照片
No. We had our squatter take a look at mug shots
辨认安东・弗朗西斯的同伙  但没结果
Of Anton Francis' associates, and we didn't find him.
如果这第三人不是通过刀疤脸
What if the connection to the third man
接应的
isn't through scar face?
-而是通过道格呢  -旅行社
- What if it's through Doug? - The travel agent?
不是查得一清二楚了吗
I thought we went through him.
没错  查了他的家人朋友和同事
We did. We checked his family, his friends, his coworkers.
可没查他的客户
But not his clients.
你想啊  或许就是客户
Think about it. Maybe that's it.
这第三人通过道格订票
The third man books a trip through Doug.
道格开始向他讲述自己的梦想
Doug starts talking, tells him about his dream
在岛上拥有自己的潜水用品商店
of owning a scuba shop in the islands.
神秘人感觉到他的挫败  拉他入伙
The third man senses his frustration. That's his in.
他告诉道格事情很容易
He tells Doug it'll be easy.
利己不损人  没人有损失
It's a victimless crime, nobody will get hurt,
保险公司会赔偿
Insurance will pay,
神秘人心里清楚  如果警察调查
knowing the whole time, if the police investigate,
会追踪到道格  而不是他
they'll track the tickets back through to Doug, not to him.
只要道格一死
The third man remains invisible
-神秘人就蒸发了  -算是合理
- so long as Doug is dead. - That almost makes sense.
查查道格最近半年的客户名单
Let's run Doug's client list for the past six months.
-如有可疑人物  拿给米齐认认  -好
- If anything pops, we'll show it to Mickey. - Okay.
或许今晚应该取消
You know, maybe I should cancel tonight.
他冒了生命危险救狗
You're gonna cancel on the guy
你还要放人家鸽子
that risked his life for a bunch of puppies?
长官  你知道我的约会
Sir, you know about my date?
是的  不管你会怎么想
Yes, and--and despite what you might think,
你消失一晚
The world's not gonna end
地球不会不转的
just because you disappear for a night.
就算你不在  我肯定他俩能应付
And if it does, I'm sure that those two can handle it.
-是的  去吧  -是啊  我要加班
- Yeah. Go ahead. - Yeah, I need the overtime.
那有消息立即通知我
Okay, but call me if anything turns up.
好好好  玩得开心点
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Have fun.
看她像是要取消约会吗
You see how ready she was to cancel on that date?
跟你有什么关系  卡塞尔
What's it to you, Castle?
是啊  你管那么多呢
Yeah, why do you care?
随便说说  关心一下...
I'm just sayin'. Look out 'cause, uh...
都不好
Neither of those.
看这个
Mm. Look.
这个好
Oh, you're good.
我知道你会觉得奇怪
I know that this can be weird for you,
-父母不该去约会  -我知道你去约会  爸爸
- How parents aren't supposed to date. - I know you date, dad.
还知道你可能会做其他事
I know you probably do other things
那个我可懒得想
that I am not going to think about,
过去将来  我们都不会提及此事
And that we'll never, ever mention.
行  怎么了
Fair enough. So... what's wrong?
不知道
I don't know.
我没法一直在你身边
I mean, I'm not gonna be here forever.
到时候谁照顾你呢
And then who's gonna look after you then,
排名第三的未婚佳丽
bachelorette number 3?
且慢
Slow down there.
不会这么快就买戒指吧
Let's not go buying rings anytime soon.
-只是个约会  -我知道
- It's just a date. - I know.
她看起来不错  不过...
And she seems nice and all, but...
如果挑选约会对象
if that's who you date,
我是说  你真的只和
I mean, are you really gonna find happiness
上了榜的人追求幸福吗
with the kind of person who's a number on a list?
已然如此
Well, I already have.
你是我个人名单上的冠军
You're number one on mine.
关心你是我的责任
Look, it's my job to worry about you,
不能倒过来
not the other way around.
-我很好  -是啊
-I'll be fine. -Yeah.
你准备炸火鸡时也这么说的
That's what you said when you tried to deep-fry a turkey.
我们都记得结果如何
And we all know how that turned out.
我只是不想你受伤
I just don't want you to get hurt...
或再一次燎了你的眉毛
or burn your eyebrows off... again.
很高兴眉毛又长了出来
I'm glad they grew back.
终于长得一样了
They're finally matching.
听说这里订不到位子
I've heard this place is impossible to get into.
借过
Excuse me.
-里克  -弗朗克  过来
- Ricky. - Frankie! Come here.
-真高兴又见面了  -是啊
- It's nice to see you again. - And you.
你们的位子马上就好
Um, your table will be ready momentarily.
卡塞尔
Castle?
贝克特
Beckett?
-我猜你们是认识的  -是的
- I take it you two know each other? - Uh, yeah.
布拉德  这是理查德・卡塞尔  我的同事
Brad, this is Richard Castle. We work together.
阿曼达  这是凯特・贝克特  我的同事
Uh, Amanda, this is Kate Beckett. We work together.
认识你很高兴
Hi. Nice to meet you.
你在这里做什么
Ah. What are you doing here?
-你知道我要来  -我知道你想来
-You knew that I was coming here. -I knew you wanted to come here.
我以为这么晚你订不到位子
I didn't think you could get a table last-minute.
你这么晚还是订到了位子
You got a table last-minute.
-是的  我找的人  -我也是  市卫生检察员
- Yeah. I've got connections. - So do I. City health inspector.
充分滥用了职权
Wow. Nice abuse of power.
理查德  你也是警察
So, Richard, you a cop, too?
不  他是小说家  查案时的
No. He's a novelist who's been shadowing me
-跟班  -我比跟班做的多一点
- on my murder cases. - Oh, I do a little more than shadowing.
二位可以入座了
Your table is ready.
你们一起调查凶杀案
So you two working a homicide?
有两名死者的凶杀案
Um, a double homicide.
实际上非常棘手  因为凶手是...
It's actually a rather tricky case because the killer is...
我喜欢称他神秘第三人
I like to call him the third man.
真神秘啊  听着像你的小说
Very mysterious. It sounds like one of your books.
是的  有点类似
Yeah, it kinda does.
-不管怎样  他和两个同伙...  -要抢劫银行
- Anyway, he and his two partners... - were gonna rob a bank,
但任务还没完成
only he turned on the other two
他就杀死了自己的两个同伙
and killed them before they even finished the job.
是不是根本不合理
I mean, it doesn't even make any sense.
罪犯通常拿到了钱
Usually you'd wait until you got the money
才出卖同伙
before you double-crossed your partners.
抢劫银行  他们连装备都没备齐
I mean, they didn't even have the right equipment to rob a bank.
我相信  你最后会查明真相的
Well, I'm sure you'll figure it out eventually.
说到奇闻秘事
You know, speaking of great mysteries,
那晚  我在百老汇看了一出
I saw an incredible play off broadway
-不错的剧目  -我真希望能查明
- the other night. - I just wish I could figure out
他们用氯氨酮干什么
what they were doing with the ketamine.
或许跟宠物店有关
Maybe it had something to do with the pet store.
你要吃那个吗
You gonna eat that?
那里不像是有什么能偷的啊
It's not like there was really anything to steal there.
除非宠物店是其他东西的幌子
Unless the pet store was just a front for something else.
服务员  请再给我一杯酒
Waiter. Could I have another glass of wine, please?
这种情况下  店主说没什么可偷的
In which case, the owner might have been lying
可能是在撒谎
when he said that nothing was stolen.
过一会想跟我上床吗
You want to have sex with me later?
抱歉  介意我打个电话吗
I'm sorry. Would you mind if I made a telephone call?
当然不会
Nah.
谢谢
Thanks.
洗手间就在前台旁边  对吧
Um... the bathrooms are up by the front, right?
请原谅
Pardon me.
有什么消息吗
Have you got something?
我让莱恩和埃斯波西托帮我查点东西
I was just having Ryan and Esposito run something down for me.
宠物店
The pet shop.
-是的  你怎么知道  -心有灵犀
- Yes! How did you know? - I was thinking the exact same thing.
很可能是什么东西的幌子
It's probably a front for something.
关于店主  他们会彻查的
Okay, so they're gonna dig up everything they can on the owner.
-也许他有所隐瞒  -没错
- It could be that he's hiding something. - Right.
-我该回去了  -约会如何
- Well, I should get back to this date. - How's yours going?
-好极了  你呢  -棒极了
- Great. Yours? - Fantastic.
回头见
Well, I'll, uh, see you.
野鸡肉鲜美可口
The pheasant is amazing.
抱歉  是局里打来的
I'm sorry. That's the station.
是的  接吧
Yeah. Go ahead.
请原谅
Would you pardon me?
又去洗手间
Bathroom again?
查到了什么吗
So what'd they find out?
是的
Yo.
查了宠物店店主  诺埃尔・杜・普利
We ran the pet shop owner-- Noel Du Preez.
-身家清白  -真的
- He came up clean. - Really?
在过去的几天里呢
What about in the past couple of days?
有何异常吗
Anything unusual?
前天  海关方面查到他那有
The day before yesterday, customs has him taking possession
六只非洲灰鹦鹉  四只狒狒蜘蛛
of a half a dozen African gray parrots, four baboon spiders
两条黑尾纹巨蟒  都来自南非
and two black-tailed pythons, all from south Africa.
等等
Wait a minute. Did you--
你说南非的黑尾蟒
did you say black-tailed pythons from South Africa?
是  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
因为黑尾蟒
Because black-tailed pythons,
也叫印度岩蟒
also known as Indian rock pythons,
并非生于非洲
are not indigenous to that area.
为什么会从那里运过来呢
Why would they be coming from Africa?
管那吓人飞机上
Why do you care about some motherfreaking snakes
吓死人的蛇干嘛
on a motherfreaking plane?
作为一个侦探小说家
Because as a murder mystery novelist,
我必须了解罪犯的想法
I am highly paid to think like a bad guy.
蛇有几个有意思的特点
Here are a few fun facts about snakes.
它们是冷血动物  能吞下巨物
They are cold-blooded, they swallow huge amounts,
并且消化得很慢
and they digest their food very slowly.
正适合走私
Perfect for smuggling.
这肯定不是初犯了
And it wouldn't be the first time.
如果这些蟒蛇来自南非
If these snakes are coming in from South Africa...
南非盛产两样东西
There are two things in abundance in South Africa--
种族仇恨和钻石
racial hatred and diamonds.
在活蛇体内走私钻石
Smuggling diamonds in live snakes.
袭击米齐的人说事关几百万
Mickey's attacker said that there were millions at stake.
而且升降机直通宠物店
and the dumbwaiter goes right down into the pet store.
所以梅特兰一家必须本周出行
That's why the Maitlands' trip had to be this week.
他们知道货就要到了
They knew the shipment was coming in.
-氯胺酮  -用来麻醉蟒蛇
- And the ketamine-- - was to dope the snakes.
他们就可以不费吹灰之力取货
So they could take 'em up the shaft without a fight,
我们去宠物店时
and then when we came to the store--
店主三缄其口
The owner couldn't say a word,
他怕收到走私案的牵连
otherwise he'd implicate himself in smuggling.
一旦我们找到劫犯
So we find out who robbed him--
我们就找到了第三个人
We find the third man.
他们知道彼此说话珠联璧合吗
Do they know they're finishing each other's sentences?
让同事逮捕店主  在店里集合
Have uniforms pick up the owner. We'll meet you at the store.
这里有人吗
Hey, is this seat taken?
我们要跟他们说什么呢
What should we tell them?
太尴尬了
This is gonna be awkward.
他们会相处愉快的
They'll be okay.
缉拿到店主了吗
Is the owner in custody?
他妻子说他还在这里加班
Wife said he was here working late.
看起来已经打烊了
Place looks closed.
卡塞尔  帮我拿包
Okay, Castle, hold my purse.
跟上
Follow me.
准备好了吗  走
Ready? Let's go.
房间里没人
Room all clear.
这里也是
Here, too.
纽约警察  放下武器
NYPD! Drop your weapon! Drop your weapon!
把枪放下
Drop the gun! Drop your weapon! Drop the gun!
把枪放下  趴下
Drop the gun! Get down! Down!
你没事吧
Hey. You okay?
这点小事吓不倒我
It takes a lot more than that to scare me.
如果你肩膀上有一只毛茸茸的大蜘蛛呢
What about a big, hairy spider on your shoulder?
那会吓我一跳
Yeah, that would do it.
我怎么知道你们是警察
How did I know you were the police?
我有权保护自己的店
I have a right to defend my store.
你要提防谁  杜・普利先生
Defend from who, Mr. Du Preez?
根据海关的记录
According to customs,
你有两条黑尾蟒
you took possession of two black-tailed pythons.
这又没犯罪
Which is not a crime.
但黑尾蟒原产于印度
No, but black-tailed pythons are indigenous to India.
为什么要从南非运来呢
So why ship them in from South Africa?
我的供应商在那里
My suppliers are there.
我的生意合理合法
There's nothing illegal about my business.
那些蛇在哪儿呢
Then where are the snakes?
没在店里
They weren't in the store,
而且没有发票能证明已售
and we didn't find any invoices indicating that they were sold.
你知道我们找到什么了吗
You know what we did find?
一个比色计  一盏紫外灯和克拉秤
A color grader, a U.V. lamp and a carat weight scale.
都是买卖钻石所需的工具
All tools of the diamond trade.
怎么回事  杜・普利先生
So what happened, Mr. Du Preez?
我们认为有人从升降机通道
Because we think someone broke into your store,
闯入你的店里
came down the dumbwaiter shaft
偷走了你的钻石
and stole your shipment of diamonds.
那是你的问题
Now that's your problem.
我的问题是那两具尸体
My problem is that they left two bodies behind.
你不想受牵连  我明白
Okay, fine. You don't want to implicate yourself. I get it.
那我提问  运货的事都有谁知道
So I'm simply gonna ask, who knew about the shipment?
拜托  杜・普利先生
Come on, Mr. Du Preez.
你不想知道他们是谁吗
Don't you want us to find them?
谁知道  你告诉过谁
Who knew? Who did you tell?
我谁都没告诉
I told no one.
杜・普利先生
Mr. Du Preez--
我自己去机场取的货
I picked up my cargo at the airport personally,
把它们锁在办公室里
and I locked 'em in my office.
第二天  就不见了
The next day, they were gone.
你认识这些人吗
Do you recognize either of these men?
没有  这些人我从来都没见过
No. I've never seen any of them in my life.
我说的是实话
It's the truth.
抢劫走私贩  真是完美的犯罪
Robbing a smuggler. It's almost a perfect crime.
受害者不能报警
The victim can't go to the police
除非认罪
without admitting his own crime.
有人知道货物放在哪里
Someone knew that shipment was coming in.
而且蓄谋已久
Someone had it planned.
道格的客户名单调查得如何
Where are we on Doug's client list?
查了道格的所有客户
We ran every client Doug ever had,
一无所获
and we got Nada.
为求万全
Just to be thorough,
还给米齐看了车管局那边的照片
we showed their D.M.V. Photos to Mickey.
他们都不是神秘的第三人
None of them were our mysterious third man.
一定是杜・普利想不到的人
Well, it had to be someone Du Preez would never expect.
与宠物店有关的人
Someone connected to his pet store in some capacity,
可能是前雇员吗
an old employee perhaps?
他得知道货物何时运达
He would have to know when the shipment was coming in.
知道他时间表的人
Yeah, someone who knew his timetable.
也许是杜・普利之前派去机场
Maybe somebone Du Preez had sent to the airport previously
取货的人
to pick up a shipment.
去机场
Out to the airport.
干什么
What was that?
查查上次杜・普利取货的记录
Run all of the paperwork from Du Preez's last shipment--
海关方面  检疫方面  物流公司等等
customs, fish and wildlife, shipping company, everything.
查什么人知道货物及取货时间
I want to know who knew what and when.
你是说有人在机场看到杜・普利走私
You think someone at the airport caught on to Du Preez's smuggling,
决定抢劫而非报警
decided to rob him instead of report him?
不仅如此  我想我知道是谁了
Not only that. I think I know who.
科佩克夫妇  谢谢你们这么晚还能来
Mr. And Mrs. Kopek, thank you for coming in so late.
请坐
Please.
对不起  这么久才到
Oh, sorry, it took so long.
你打电话的时候  斯坦正在工作
Stan was at work when you called.
没事
Oh, right.
你说过最后见到你弟弟是在
You said that the last time that you saw your brother
旅行社在斯坦公司举行的派对上  是吗
was at the agency's party around where Stan works?
没错
That's right.
科佩克先生  你能重新告诉我
Could you refresh my memory, Mr. Kopek?
你在哪里工作吗
Where is it that you work?
夜深了
It--it's late.
能直接告诉我们调查结果吗
Could--could you just please tell us what you found out?
直到我想起来
Well, I didn't really put everything together
你妻子说过在机场的派对
until I remembered your wife's story
我才把一切都联系起来
about the party at the airport.
这是什么
What's this?
这是一份海关申报表  科佩克先生
It's a customs form, Mr. Kopek,
允许诺埃尔・杜・普利先生
Authorizing the release of cargo
取货
to a Mr. Noel Du Preez,
你签的字
Signed by you.
那又怎样  我在海关工作
Yeah. So? I-I work for customs.
那又怎样
What's-- what's the big deal?
怎么了  斯坦
What's going on, Stan?
我不知道
I have no idea.
别装傻了
Sure you do.
当你知道杜・普利
When you realized what Mr. Du Preez was doing--
走私钻石  你对自己说
smuggling diamonds-- you said to yourself,
"何必放过那些忘恩负义的混蛋
"Why should I give him up to those ungrateful bastards?
为什么不给自己谋些好处呢"
"Why not just take care of myself?"
你需要做的只是
Then all you needed to do
从动物保护中心偷看进口许可
was pull the import permits from fish and wildlife
来决定动手的时间
to determine when the next shipment would be.
但你还需要找到
But you needed someone with connections
能入室盗窃的人
to fencing stolen goods.
所以你联系了安东・弗朗西斯
And so you contacted Anton Francis--
骗子  高中老同学
a con man and an old high school buddy
进出监狱多年的家伙
who'd been in and out of jail for years.
用钱就可以买通他
The easy score was money to his ears,
但你需要梅特兰一家
but you needed to get the Maitlands out of town
先离开几天
for a couple of days first.
此时你就拉小舅子道格入伙了
And that's when your brother-in-law Doug came in.
你做了什么  斯坦
What did you do, Stan?
你是不是利用了他的梦想
Did you play on his dreams,
跟他说  他能实现开潜水用品店的梦想了
tell him he could finally afford that scuba shop he always wanted?
斯坦  你做了什么
Stan, what did you do?
我什么都没做  我不知道
Nothing. Nothing. I-I don't know--
科佩克太太  你丈夫杀死了你弟弟
Mrs. Kopek, your husband killed your brother.
-太荒...  -斯坦...
- That's ri-- - Stan...
他们撒谎  这太荒谬了
They're lying. That's-- that's ridiculous.
我们有证人  科佩克先生
We have a witness, Mr. Kopek.
几十分钟前  你想要杀死的
The squatter you tried to kill
违法借住客
identified you from a photo array
在照片中指认了你
less than an hour ago.
天啊
Oh, god.
不  我也不想这样的
No, no, it was--it wasn't supposed to happen like this.
我没想伤他
N-no one was supposed to get hurt.
道格  他不听我说的
I mean, Doug--he just-- he wouldn't listen.
我不是说...
And I-I didn't mean...
安东  他在我后面
And--and Anton, he came after me.
他...  那是自卫  我不是凶手
He--that was self-defense. I'm not--I'm not a killer.
我们有两具尸体证明你是凶手
We have two bodies that prove otherwise.
事情发展不受控制了
It just got out of hand. Things just spun out of control.
-把他带走吧  -宝贝
- Get him away from me. - Honey, it's--
站起来
On your feet.
我为了我们才这么做的
I did it for us.
都是为了我们  宝贝
It was all for us, baby.
你们认为是我瞎编的
And you guys thought I made the whole thing up.
我可一直都相信你
I believed you the whole time.
我现在会怎样
So what--what happens to me now?
回拘留室
I'll go back to the holding cell
还是要入土了
or am I headed to the tombs?
都不是  你配合我们逮捕斯坦・科佩克
Neither. For your cooperation in the apprehension
检察官助理同意宽大处理
of Stan Kopek, the A.D.A. has agreed to a deal.
五年缓刑
Five years probation for all your sins.
不用坐牢
No jail time?
你有了重新做人的机会  米齐
You have a shot at a second chance, Mickey.
别搞砸了
Don't blow it.
不会的  谢谢
I won't. Hey, thanks for everything.
真的  谢谢
Really, thank you.
我等不及回家
Oh, man. I can't wait to go home
-洗个热水澡了  -我
- and just slip into a warm bath and-- - I--
别  别说
Don't. Please don't.
我只是想说  我饿死了
I was just going to say, I'm starving.
我还没吃完主菜  就离开餐厅了
We left the restaurant before I had a chance to finish my entree.
你吃完了也没用
Oh, yeah. Well, it wouldn't have mattered if you did.
那里菜量很小
The portions there were tiny.
你知道雷米餐厅二十四小时营业
You know, Remy's is open all night.
他们有汉堡
They've got those burgers...
还有奶昔
Oh, and those shakes...
为什么不去呢
Oh, why not?
你的约会怎么样
So how did your date go?
她很无聊
She was kind of boring.
没说几句话
Didn't talk much.
七月先生呢
Mr. July?
-有点自负  -看出来了
- A little self-absorbed. - Looked it.
-真的吗  -能看得出
- Really? - You can tell.
约会时  有些人就是没法表现得体
Some people just don't know how to behave on a date.
-尤其是第一次约会  -说得好
- Especially on a first date. - Exactly.